Amr Mohamed

Senior iOS Software Engineer

(Swift, Combine, RXSwift, MVVM, SwiftUI).

Cairo, Egypt
+201004676701
iAmrMohamed.me
iAmrMohamed@gmail.com
Github Linkedin Leetcode

SUMMARY

Highly skilled and experienced iOS Software Engineer with more than 8 years experience in developing iOS mobile applications, worked on more than 30 iOS apps across 3 different software house companies which helped me work on a wide range of native and 3rd party frameworks and allowed me to have a deep and up to date knowledge of the core iOS development principles.

OPEN SOURCE

- · DigitEntryView iOS digit input field with multiple styles designed for entering OTP codes.
- <u>SlideUpSheet</u> custom presentation controller that slides up from the bottom and can be dismissed with a swipe down pan down gesture with a dynamic background that dims when swiping.
- <u>BlurPopover</u> popover custom presentation controller with a dynamic blur background that changes the blur radius when swiped up and down with a title and dismiss button like navigation bars.
- <u>AMKeyboardFrameTracker</u> keyboard frame tracker that gets attached to inputAccessoryView to track the current keyboard frame to emulate the interactive keyboard dismissal effect.
- <u>AMVideoRangeSlider</u> and <u>AMSloMoRangeSlider</u> video range sliders that replicate the native iOS range slider, designed for dragging a slider between a specific range of video content.

WORK EXPERIENCE



Botit

Leading e-commerce platform serving in the Middle East.

Apr 2018 - Present · 5 yrs 6 mos

Senior Software Engineer

- Rearchitected the entire codebase from MVC to MVVM using RXSwift initially and then Combine later resulting in a significant improvement in the entire code maintainability and testability.
- Took the initiative to build 3 widgets using **SwiftUI** for the iOS 14.0 home screen, which lead us to rewriting over 20% of the app being revamped into **SwiftUI** components enhancing many of the complicated components in the app.
- Implemented fully automated release process using **GitHub Actions** and **Fastlane**, reducing deployment time by **70**%, allowing us to deploy more frequently and streamlined app updates.
- Contributed to the hiring process of the iOS developer candidates by assisting in the screening and the evaluation of the technical skills.
- Mentored junior and mid-level developers, providing guidance on best practices and ensuring code
 quality through regular code reviews and conducting pair programming sessions resulting in
 improved productivity and higher quality code.

iOS Software Engineer

- Over a span of more than 5 years working on this app, I've consistently contributed across the entire development lifecycle, engaging comprehensively with nearly every aspect of its feature set.
- Built more than 3 custom **Presentation Controllers** and custom **Interactive Animated Transitions** resulting in a huge improvement in the user experience flow across the entire app.
- Built an internal WebSocket wrapper around the native URLSession to facilitate the use of web sockets in the app with 80% test coverage for the wrapper.
- Introduced **Bitrise** CI/CD pipelines to automate **TestFlight** builds and run **Unit Tests**, resulting in significant time savings and improved overall development efficiency.



Beetleware — iOS Software Engineer

Software House Company with more than 70 developers.

Feb 2016 - Mar 2018 · 2 yrs 2 mos

- Worked on more than 10 apps apps and monitored 5 junior developers in my team.
- Introduced MVVM design pattern resulting in a huge improvement in code maintainability and testability while also simplifying development workflows and reducing code complexity.
- Took the initiative to automate the deployment process by using a continuous delivery service.
- Built a **networking framework** streamlining all types of networking calls across all company apps, resulting in a dramatic 90% improvement in the speed of building networking layers for new apps.
- Aseel is a crowd-investing development services in Saudi Arabia.
- Mahsol, Hayati, Hashi Basha food ordering apps.
- TabibyLive, <u>Doctors</u>, <u>Patients</u> digital healthcare booking platform.
- DocEgy, <u>Doctors</u>, <u>Patients</u> digital healthcare booking platform.
- <u>Rest4Rest</u>, <u>Rest4Rest Supplier</u>, <u>Rest4Rest Delivery</u> multi-platform operational solutions for restaurants and hotels.



ABG EGYPT — iOS Software Engineer

Software House Company

Nov 2014 - Jan 2016 · 1 yr 3 mos

- Worked on more than 5 apps apps with a team of 7 developers.
- <u>Johnson KSA</u> worked on a **3D** rendering view using **SceneKit**, that shows cars in a **3D** environment and allows the customers to change the tint color of car glasses.
- <u>E-Toggar</u> and <u>Kreaz</u> are e-commerce apps for selling online products.
- Elogra fare calculator app that helps passengers calculate the fare for public rides.
- Ewsally on-demand offers platform that provides personalized deals to users based on location.



KlarApps — iOS Software Developer

Software House Company

Mar 2014 - Oct 2014 · 8 mos

- Built my very first 2 apps from scratch.
- I used mostly MVC as a design pattern for all the apps.
- <u>Taahel</u> social platform that serve people with special needs, **Taahel** was a huge app I learned tons of new stuff and worked on more than 120 screens across the entire app.
- Spare is a social platform for selling car parts online.

INDEPENDENT & CONTRACT IOS ENGINEER

- <u>Ekeif</u> social platform that means E-How for watching how to videos.
- Almasar dubai's RTA official monthly magazine.
- <u>SlooMo</u> captures, edits, exports videos into slow motion videos.

EDUCATION

University of Sinai, El-Arish, North Sinai,

B.S in Information Technology, 2012 - 2016.

PROFICIENT

Swift, Combine, RxSwift, MVVM, MVC, Coordinator, SwiftUI, Clean Architecture, CoreData, Realm, GitFlow, CI/CD, Fastlane, Xcode Cloud, Unit Tests, UI Tests, Agile, JIRA, Problem Solving.